Habaek.
Habaek.
Nak-bin was going to be used as a sacrificial offering.
Nak-bin akan menjadi korban persembahan.
Human sacrifice.
Korban manusia.
It's what foolish humans used to do.
Itu yang biasa dilakukan manusia bodoh.
But Habaek fell in love with the human offering given to us,
Tapi Habaek jatuh cinta pada korban itu,
so shall we say that he was even more foolish than humans?
jadi, dia bahkan lebih bodoh daripada manusia?
The King of the Land of the Sky had a vain dream of
Raja Negeri Langit punya mimpi besar
breaking the rules of the divine realm and building a new order.
membongkar aturan alam suci dan membangun tatanan baru.
He thought he could achieve it by stealing Habaek's powers.
Dia pikir bisa mencapainya dengan mencuri kekuatan Habaek.
Habaek.
Habaek.
He promised Habaek's woman eternal life,
Dia menjanjikan kehidupan abadi bagi wanita Habaek
and that foolish woman gladly promised him that she'd betray Habaek.
dan wanita itu dengan senang berjanji akan mengkhianati Habaek.
Thus, she fooled Habaek and put him under the curse.
Karena itu, dia membohongi Habaek dan membuatnya dikutuk.
Do you think she ended up gaining eternal life that she so longed for?
Apa dia akhirnya hidup abadi seperti yang dia dambakan?
The sun will go down soon.
Matahari akan tenggelam.
Nak-bin.
Nak-bin.
Habaek.
Habaek.
The Queen Mother...
Ibu Suri...
wants to kill you.
ingin membunuhmu.
She wants to use your blood...
Dia ingin pakai darahmu...
to break the curse you brought upon us.
untuk menghancurkan kutukan yang kau berikan pada kami.
The eternal life you've been desperately longing for
Kehidupan abadi yang kau idamkan
will be granted to you along with death.
akan bersama dengan kematian.
Neither nirvana nor reincarnation...
Baik nirwana maupun reinkarnasi...
will be allowed.
akan terjadi.
Help me.
Tolong aku.
Please.
Kumohon.
Save me, Habaek. Please.
Selamatkan aku, Habaek. Kumohon.
I will...
Aku tak akan...
never forgive you.
memaafkanmu.
I came to tell you this.
Aku beri tahu ini.
Habaek, I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Habaek, maafkan. Aku sangat menyesal.
Please, Habaek! I didn't know.
Tolong, Habaek. Aku tak tahu.
I had no idea that it was a curse.
Aku tak tahu itu kutukan.
I did it out of love.
Aku melakukannya karena cinta.
I wanted to live eternally with you.
Aku ingin hidup abadi bersamamu.
I love you, Habaek. I love you...
Aku mencintaimu, Habaek. Aku mencintaimu...
Please. I love you.
Kumohon. Aku mencintaimu.
Habaek!
Habaek!
Habaek.
Habaek.
Please don't kill me!
Tolong jangan bunuh aku.
Please!
Kumohon!
No! Please!
Tidak! Kumohon!
No.
Tidak.
Habaek! Habaek! Help me!
Habaek! Tolong aku!
Habaek, please help me.
Habaek, tolong bantu aku.
Habaek, please don't kill me!
Habaek. Tolong jangan bunuh aku!
Help...
Tolong…
However, taking that woman's insignificant life
Namun, mengambil nyawa wanita itu
was not enough to appease the Queen Mother's fury.
tak cukup untuk menenangkan Ibu Suri.
The Queen Mother wanted her brother and his son to pay for her sins as well.
Ibu Suri menginginkan saudaranya dan putranya untuk membayar dosa-dosanya.
Please spare our lives.
Ampuni kami.
The brother begged for mercy.
Saudaranya memohon ampun.
Then the Queen Mother asked him what he could give her in return,
Ibu Suri bertanya apa balasan yang dia berikan.
and the foolish man promised her
Pria bodoh itu berjanji
that his family would serve the gods generation after generation.
keluarganya akan melayani para dewa selamanya.
That's absurd.
Itu konyol.
And what does that have to do with me?
Apa hubungannya denganku?
Even if one of my ancestors betrayed his country,
Bahkan jika moyangku mengkhianati negara,
killed someone, or stole something a thousand years ago,
membunuh, mencuri 1.000 tahun lalu,
what does that have to do with me now?
apa hubungannya denganku kini?
Am I supposed to feel guilty for what that woman did?
Apa aku harus merasa bersalah atas perbuatannya?
Too bad. You can only feel guilty
Sayang sekali. Kau hanya bisa merasa bersalah
when you actually did something wrong.
saat kau berbuat salah.
As for this story, I can't even relate to it.
Aku tak bisa mengerti ini.
You really are foolish.
Kau sungguh bodoh.
You just don't get it, do you?
Kau tak mengerti, bukan?
What did Mura say to you?
Apa kata Mura kepadamu?
Why do you look so serious?
Kenapa kau tampak sangat serius?
Let's eat.
Ayo makan.
It's almost dinnertime.
Ini hampir makan malam.
It's pretty amazing that you guys always show up right around dinnertime.
Luar biasa kalian selalu datang tepat waktu makan malam.
Gosh, it's gone bad.
Astaga, ini sudah basi.
What should we do?
Kita harus bagaimana?
Should we have cup noodles?
Makan mi instan?
What did Mura...
Apa kata Mura...
say to you?
kepadamu?
She didn't say much. She just told me your old love story.
Dia tak bicara banyak.
It wasn't even that interesting.
Itu bahkan tak menarik.
Sit down.
Duduklah.
-Nak-bin was-- -Yes, Nak-bin.
- Nak-bin... - Ya, Nak-bin.
That was her name, right?
Itu namanya, kan?
I knew it. The story about the woman with the surname Shim was fake.
Aku tahu. Kisah wanita dengan nama keluarga Shim itu palsu.
The woman, whom you loved so dearly,
Wanita yang sangat kau cintai
betrayed you,
mengkhianatimu dan...
and she was punished eventually.
akhirnya dia dihukum.
Then her brother made a stupid pledge. And, apparently, he's my ancestor.
Lalu saudaranya membuat janji bodoh.
But the thing is, am I supposed to be responsible
Tapi apa aku harus bertanggung jawab
for what one of my ancestors did 1,200 years ago?
atas perbuatan leluhurku 1.200 tahun lalu?
Don't you think it's ridiculous?
Tidakkah itu konyol?
I'm utterly baffled.
Aku benar-benar bingung.
What is it that you really want to say?
Apa maksudmu?
Go back.
Kembalilah.
Return to where you belong.
Kembalilah ke tempatmu.
Please go back.
Tolong pergi.
And please move out as soon as possible.
Tolong keluar secepatnya.
I decide when I will leave.
Kuputuskan kapan aku akan pergi.
I heard you did nothing.
Kudengar kau diam saja.
Do whatever it takes to persuade him.
Lakukan apa pun untuk membujuknya.
When the woman you loved...
Saat wanita yang kau cintai...
was dying,
sekarat...
you did nothing.
kau tak melakukan apa pun.
You really are foolish.
Kau memang egois.
You just don't get it, do you?
Kau tak mengerti, bukan?
I'm not telling you to feel guilty.
Aku tak menyuruhmu merasa bersalah.
I'm asking you to let Habaek go.
Aku minta kau biarkan Habaek pergi.
Let him go.
Lepaskan dia.
I know you can figure out that is what you should do.
Aku tahu kau paham itu yang harus kau lakukan.
It makes me so angry to admit this,
Aku sangat marah mengakui ini, tapi harus kuakui.
That fool...
Si Bodoh itu...
is in love with you.
jatuh cinta padamu.
Do you understand?
Apa kau mengerti?
He'll go back anyway.
Dia akan kembali.
But he's torn.
Tapi tidak.
He can't only think about himself.
Dia tak bisa egois.
Habaek represents the Land of Water,
Habaek mewakili Negeri Air,
which is everything to him.
itu segalanya baginya.
Like you said, he has to go back eventually.
Seperti katamu, dia akan kembali.
Do you know what the biggest irony is?
Apa kau tahu ironinya?
If he doesn't ascend the throne,
Jika dia tak naik takhta...
he'll be nothing.
dia bukan siapa-siapa.
That means Habaek will choose to go back, no matter how torn he is now.
Itu artinya Habaek akan kembali, apa pun kondisinya sekarang.
Then everything is fine.
Semuanya akan baik.
Let him go before he destroys himself...
Lepaskan dia sebelum dia menghancurkan dirinya...
while he still has the strength to get over it.
selagi dia masih bisa melupakannya.
Let him go, please.
Biarkan dia pergi.
After losing Nak-bin,
Setelah kehilangan Nak-bin...
he punished himself and became a wreck.
dia menghukum dirinya dan jadi hancur.
I don't want to see that again.
Aku tak mau melihatnya lagi.
I beg you.
Kumohon.
Please don't hold him back,
Tolong jangan menahannya...
like Nak-bin did.
seperti Nak-bin.
I wish I could cry.
Andai aku bisa menangis.
Like you said,
Seperti katamu...
I wish I could get drunk.
kuharap aku bisa mabuk.
I wish I could do...
Kuharap aku bisa melakukan hal bodoh yang dilakukan manusia.
I'm so angry.
Aku sangat marah.
This anger is driving me nuts.
Kemarahan ini membuatku gila.
I admitted in front of her
Aku akui padanya...
that he's in love with her.
dia mencintainya.
You didn't have to.
Itu tak perlu.
Why did that have to be...
Kenapa itu satu-satunya cara...
the only way I could send him back?
agar bisa mengembalikannya?
Then you did what you had to do.
Lakukan yang harus kau lakukan.
You don't need to be angry...
Kau tak perlu marah...
or regret anything.
atau menyesali apa pun.
I'll give you a hug.
Akan kupeluk.
If you'd let me,
Jika kau mengizinkanku...
Don't you dare.
Jangan coba-coba.
See? I knew you'd say that.
Lihat? Sudah kuduga.
Namsuri.
Namsuri.
Wake up, Namsuri.
Bangun, Namsuri.
-Where were you yesterday? -Here and there.
- Di mana kau kemarin? - Di mana-mana.
Were your feelings hurt because I worked to get a gift for the servant?
Apa kau sakit hati karena aku bekerja untuk hadiah pelayan itu?
Pardon? Oh, well...
Apa? Ya...
Yes, it really hurt my feelings.
itu menyakiti perasaanku.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
You drive the duck boat during the day in the scorching heat
Kau pengemudi perahu bebek di siang hari yang terik
and work as a delivery guy at night while battling mosquitoes.
dan jadi kurir di malam hari melawan nyamuk.
I know you're doing all of that to serve me well.
Aku tahu kau melakukannya untuk melayaniku dengan baik.
Even though I'm strong and healthy, all I do is take warm baths
Meski aku kuat dan sehat, aku mandi air hangat
and enjoy the food, books, and fruit juice you get me.
dan menikmati makanan, buku, dan jus buah darimu.
All I do is eat and drink.
Aku hanya makan dan minum.
I'm well aware of it.
Aku menyadari itu.
No! Please forgive me for my grave sins, My Lord!
Tidak! Ampunilah aku atas dosa beratku, Tuanku!
You weren't actually expecting me to say such things, were you?
Kau tak berharap aku mengatakan itu, bukan?
No, My Lord.
Tidak, Tuanku.
Then go tell the servant...
Maka beri tahu pelayan itu...
that we should have breakfast.
kita harus sarapan.
Pardon? Sure, right away.
Apa? Baik, sekarang juga.
That was a good meal.
Makanannya enak.
Give me your phone.
Berikan ponselmu.
Take care of them for us.
Jaga mereka.
I heard that the service needs to be canceled.
Batalkan layanannya.
The newspaper too.
Koran juga.
Please also get rid of my clothes and books.
Tolong singkirkan pakaian dan bukuku.
What do you mean, My Lord?
Apa maksudmu, Tuan?
Also, call Namsuri's boss at the duck boat tour company for him.
Dan hubungi bos Namsuri di usaha kapal bebek.
Don't stay out late.
Jangan pulang larut.
I heard there's a type of light
Kudengar ada semacam lampu
that turns on automatically when it gets dark.
yang menyala otomatis saat gelap.
Get it for your door.
Pasang untuk pintumu.
And don't eat cup noodles all the time.
Jangan makan mi instan setiap saat.
Make yourself proper meals, even if you're not a good cook.
Buat makanan yang baik walau kau bukan koki yang hebat.
Also, don't clean the house once every million years.
Juga jangan bersihkan rumah setiap sejuta tahun.
Try to clean often.
Seringlah bersih-bersih.
It'll be easier that way.
Itu lebih mudah.
For the streetlight in the alley,
Untuk lampu jalan di gang...
I heard you can submit a complaint when it's not working.
kudengar kau bisa ajukan keluhan jika rusak.
Even if it feels a hassle, it's better than walking in the dark.
Itu merepotkan, tapi lebih baik daripada jalan dalam gelap.
Just submit a complaint.
Kirim saja keluhan.
You enjoy doing things like that anyway.
Kau senang melakukan itu.
Well...
Nah...
-Namsuri. -Yes?
Namsuri.
Give us some privacy.
Tinggalkan kami.
Sure.
Tentu.
I told you that it shows on your face when you lie. Do you remember?
Kubilang mukamu berubah saat berbohong. Ingat?
But this time, I couldn't tell.
Tapi kali ini, aku tak tahu.
I've realized that you truly want me to leave.
Aku sadar kau sungguh ingin aku pergi.
I told you that I'm your god...
Kubilang aku dewamu
and bluffed that I'd protect you.
dan aku menggertak aku akan melindungimu.
It embarrasses me.
Itu membuatku malu.
Why did I make a promise that I cannot keep?
Bagaimana aku bisa berjanji yang tak bisa kutepati?
I regret it.
Aku menyesalinya.
I want to ask you if I can leave...
Aku mau bertanya apa aku bisa pergi...
and if you'll be okay.
dan kau baik-baik saja.
I want to ask you how you really feel,
Aku ingin tahu perasaanmu...
but you'll probably be okay because I've done nothing for you.
tapi tampaknya kau akan baik karena aku tak melakukan apa pun untukmu.
I'll be fine.
Aku akan baik-baik saja.
Like you said yourself, you've done nothing for me.
Kau tak lakukan apa pun untukku.
Your absence won't even be noticeable.
Ketidakhadiranmu tak berarti.
I'll be a bit lonely, but I'll be fine.
Akan agak sepi, tapi aku akan baik.
I've told you. I'm good at enduring things because I'm lesser.
Kubilang aku pandai menahannya karena aku anak kecil.
All right, then.
Baiklah.
-Are you going to leave today? -I'm leaving now.
- Pergi hari ini? - Sekarang.
Then I'll give you a ride to Gangwon Province.
Aku akan mengantarmu ke Provinsi Gangwon.
No, it's okay.
Tidak apa-apa.
Let's just part ways here.
Kita berpisah di sini.
Let's go, Namsuri.
Ayo pergi, Namsuri.
Yes, My Lord.
Ya, Tuan.
Take care, Ms. Descendant.
Jaga dirimu, Nona Keturunan.
Lord Judong told me to wait for him, though.
Tuan Judong memintaku menunggunya.
Goodbye.
Selamat tinggal.
You need a stand-in for a reporter?
Butuh pengganti reporter?
What's it about?
Tentang apa?
The sailfin...
Ikan sailfin...
Catching the sailfin sandfish?
Menangkap ikan sailfin?
The thing is, I'm prone to severe seasickness.
Masalahnya aku mabuk laut parah.
I can't really be on a small fishing boat. That's right.
Aku tak bisa berada di kapal nelayan kecil. Sungguh.
You don't want to do it?
Kau tak mau?
No, it's not that.
Bukan itu.
Gosh, I'm so disappointed.
Aku sangat kecewa.
Okay, I'll do it.
Akan kulakukan.
But you have to make sure I look very pretty in it.
Tapi kau harus memastikan aku tampak cantik.
All right. Then I'll see you tomorrow. Bye.
Baiklah. Sampai jumpa besok.
-What? -Tell him you don't want to do it.
- Apa? - Bilang kau tak mau.
What do you know?
Kau tahu apa?
If I'm that choosy, I'll never be able to make a name for myself.
Jika aku pemilih, aku tak akan bisa terkenal.
-Give me your phone. -Hey, what are you doing now?
- Berikan ponselmu. - Kau mau apa?
-Hey, Ja-ya. -Hello.
- Hai, Ja-ya. - Halo.
I'm Ja-ya's manager. You can call me Mr. Min.
Saya manajer Ja-ya, Pak Min.
-All right. What can I do for you? -Mr. Gwon.
- Apa yang bisa kubantu? - Pak Gwon.
If Ja-ya gets on the boat,
Jika Ja-ya naik kapal,
you'll need to clean it right away. Will you be okay with that?
kau harus segera membersihkannya. Kau tak keberatan?
-I have to clean it? -That's right.
- Harus bersihkan? - Ya.
She'll throw up.
Dia akan muntah.
She'll vomit nonstop.
Dia muntah tanpa henti.
Forget catching fish.
Bukannya menangkap ikan, kau harus kembali karena dia lemas.
Let's cancel it, then.
- Batalkan saja. - Kau mau batalkan?
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Mohon maaf.
Let us know if there's another good opportunity.
Beri tahu kami jika ada kesempatan lagi.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
-It's been canceled. -What?
- Dibatalkan. - Apa?
Okay, thanks.
Baik, terima kasih.
I have to deliver some juice, so I should get going.
Aku harus mengantar jus, jadi, aku harus pergi.
Stay still.
Jangan bergerak.
I told you to stay still!
Aku menyuruhmu diam!
What's wrong? Is it acting up?
Ada apa? Apakah bermasalah?
Shall I get you a new one? A mannequin, perhaps?
Mau kuambilkan yang baru? Atau manekin?
How about something that looks like Brad Pitt?
Kalau yang mirip Brad Pitt?
Does such a thing actually exist?
Apa itu benar ada?
Yes, of course.
Tentu saja. Kau suka pria tampan.
Maybe that one isn't working because it's simply not your type.
Mungkin itu tidak berhasil karena itu bukan tipemu.
Then should we try that? Although I don't love the idea.
Apa sebaiknya kita coba itu? Meski aku tak suka.
Why are you laughing?
Kenapa tertawa?
Well, do you really believe...
Apa kau benar-benar yakin
that will solve the problem?
itu akan memecahkan masalah?
The problem is you, you bonehead.
Masalahnya adalah kau bodoh.
There's nothing wrong with the actors.
Aktornya tak salah.
The problem is you.
Masalahnya adalah kau.
You scare them when you should be making them fall in love with you.
Kau menakuti mereka padahal kau harus buat mereka suka padamu.
I will freeze your tongue and--
Akan kubekukan lidahmu dan...
All right. Let's say your co-star did this.
Misalnya rekan kerjamu melakukan ini.
"Don't you dare kiss me.
"Jangan coba menciumku.
If you do, I'll freeze your tongue and crush it."
Atau akan kubekukan dan kuhancurkan lidahmu ."
If that was the message he got, would he want to kiss you?
Jika itu pemahamannya, apa dia mau menciummu?
What...
Apa...
Good. That's how you do it. Okay?
Bagus. Begitulah caramu melakukannya. Oke?
Close your mouth. You're not shooting an adult movie.
Tutup mulutmu. Kau tak syuting film dewasa.
I've been cutting you too much slack these days.
Aku terlalu sering memanjakanmu.
Let me know whenever you need someone to practice with.
Beri tahu aku jika butuh latihan.
I'd be better than a mannequin.
Aku lebih baik dari manekin.
Yes.
Ya.
Fine.
Baik.
I'll do it. I said, I'll do it!
Kubilang akan kulakukan!
Has the kissing scene been scheduled?
Adegan ciumannya dijadwalkan?
The penalty won't do, right?
Penaltinya tak akan bisa, 'kan?
Humans are like that.
Manusia memang begitu.
When their pride is hurt, even money can't do anything.
Saat harga diri mereka terluka, bahkan uang tak bisa berbuat apa-apa.
I mean, look at So-a.
Lihat saja So-a.
She returned the car as soon as Habaek left.
Dia mengembalikan mobilnya begitu Habaek pergi.
How's she holding up?
Bagaimana keadaanya?
My gosh! Stop right there.
Astaga! Hentikan.
He's such a happy, energetic kid.
Dia anak yang bahagia dan energik.
Oh, you dropped it. Good job. You're so adorable.
Kau menjatuhkannya. Kerja bagus. Kau menggemaskan.
All right, let's go over there.
Baiklah, ayo ke sana.
What an innocent little munchkin.
Munchkin kecil yang tak berdosa.
I'm really sorry.
Maafkan aku.
No problem. He has such a pure soul.
Tak masalah.
-Take care. -Bye.
- Jaga dirimu. - Dah.
Bye. See you.
Dah. Sampai jumpa.
Get home safely.
Hati-hati di jalan.
My goodness.
Astaga.
-He's so cute. -Why are you so chipper?
- Dia lucu sekali. - Kenapa kau ceria?
I'm totally frazzled.
Aku benar-benar  marah.
Isn't he cute?
Dia manis, 'kan?
You're so negative about everything.
Kau negatif pada segalanya.
That little boy is full of energy.
Anak kecil itu penuh energi.
I got a call from the bank to say we're eligible for the loan.
Ada telepon dari bank kita memenuhi syarat pinjaman.
It's all thanks to Mr. Ma's father.
Semua berkat ayah Pak Ma.
Really? That's such great news.
Sungguh? Itu kabar baik.
Contact Mr. Bang as soon as we receive the money.
Hubungi Pak Bang saat terima uangnya.
Did you tell him we'll pay more deposit?
- Kau bilang depositnya lebih banyak? - Ya.
Great, perfect. So many good things are happening. We even have more patients.
Bagus, sempurna.
We just have one new patient.
Hanya satu pasien baru.
Why are you so hyper these days?
Kenapa ceria belakangan ini?
Why are you so negative about everything?
Kenapa kau sangat negatif tentang segalanya?
Isn't that mine?
Itu punyaku?
Yes. I saw that you have a lot of this,
Ya. Aku lihat kau punya banyak,
so I took a few.
kuambil beberapa.
I want to start taking some supplements for my health.
Aku mau mulai minum suplemen untuk kesehatanku.
I should put my health before anything else.
Aku harus prioritaskan kesehatanku.
I have to stay healthy if I want to go to Vanuatu.
Harus tetap sehat jika mau ke Vanuatu.
Then buy some for yourself. Why steal mine?
Beli sendiri. Kenapa curi punyaku?
What? I stole yours?
Apa? Aku mencuri milikmu?
Hey, why are you so obsessed with these?
Kenapa kau terobsesi barang ini?
It's because Mr. Ma got them for me.
- Karena Pak Ma membelikannya untukku. - Keluar.
Dr. Yun.
Dokter Yun.
So-a, did you ask Ji-won to set you up with someone?
Apa kau minta Ji-won menjodohkanmu?
-Yes. -What?
- Ya. - Apa?
Why is she telling everyone?
Kenapa dia memberi tahu semua orang?
Oh, right. I told her to tell everyone. I'm so forgetful. Oh, dear.
Benar, kusuruh dia.
My goodness!
Astaga.
I'm sorry, guys.
Maaf.
Why are you so shocked that I'm going on a blind date?
Kenapa kau terkejut aku kencan buta?
Hey, I'm totally fine.
Aku baik-baik saja.
I knew it. It's really no big deal.
Sudah kuduga. Bukan masalah besar.
I thought I'd be devastated, but not at all.
Kupikir aku akan hancur, tapi tidak sama sekali.
Had I known it'd be this easy, I would've had more fun with him.
Andai aku tahu semudah ini, aku pasti lebih senang bersamanya.
Too bad.
Sayang sekali.
You don't get it?
Kau tak paham?
Do you know why there usually isn't much romance in crime dramas?
Tahu kenapa biasanya tak ada romansa di drama kriminal?
It's because they're too busy.
Karena mereka terlalu sibuk.
They have too many urgent problems to deal with.
Banyak masalah yang mendesak.
They're so busy solving problems that they don't have time for romance.
Saking sibuknya memecahkan masalah, tak sempat berasmara.
Do you see what I'm getting at?
Kau paham maksudku?
If I were to categorize my life under one genre, it wouldn't be romance.
Jika aku mengkategorikan hidupku dalam satu genre, itu bukan romansa.
-What I'm trying to say is-- -I heard you!
- Maksudku... - Aku paham!
I get it.
Aku mengerti.
You're embarrassing me.
Kau membuatku malu.
I'm so happy that you two broke up.
Aku senang kalian putus.
But I can't really say this is better than you crying your eyes out.
Tapi ini tidak lebih baik daripada kau menangis.
Why? I'm a psychiatrist too.
Kenapa? Aku seorang psikiater juga.
Also, romance is considered a genre as well, okay?
Romansa dianggap genre juga.
But you're a quack.
Tapi kau dukun.
You always bragged about having a knack for enduring pain.
Kau selalu sesumbar memiliki kemampuan menahan rasa sakit.
I have to get back to work. I'm expecting a patient.
Aku harus kembali bekerja. Ada pasien.
I have to say, I'm disappointed in Namsuri as well.
Harus kuakui, aku juga kecewa pada Namsuri.
I should've just made a move.
Seharusnya aku maju.
She said it wouldn't take long, so she'll be back shortly.
Dia bilang tak lama. Dia segera kembali.
Okay.
Baik.
Well...
Omong-omong...
You don't need to worry about me.
kau tak perlu khawatirkan aku.
When Dr. Yun finds a good partner,
Saat Dr. Yun menemukan rekan yang baik,
I'll be on my way. I should get married too, you know.
aku akan pergi. Aku juga harus menikah.
All right.
Baiklah.
The irony is that she has many emotional wounds because of us.
Ironisnya, dia punya banyak luka emosional karena kami.
Her father was always too busy taking care of us.
Ayahnya terlalu sibuk mengurus kami.
It is true that he was more attentive to us,
Memang dia lebih perhatian pada kita
and she was bullied in school on top of that.
dan dia dirundung di sekolah.
I even saw kids telling her to get lost,
Aku bahkan melihat yang lain mengusirnya
saying she smells like a beggar.
katanya dia bau seperti pengemis.
She hasn't told you any of this yet?
Dia belum memberitahumu ini?
I'm sorry. I thought she had already told you everything.
Maaf. Kukira dia sudah memberitahumu segalanya.
Be nicer to her, please.
Berbaiklah kepadanya.
You should dissuade her from going on that blind date.
Kau harus mencegahnya kencan buta.
Dr. Yun is going on a blind date?
Dokter Yun akan kencan buta?
Oh, you're already here.
Kau sudah di sini.
It's too late for me to apologize
Aku telat meminta maaf
for what happened last time, right?
atas apa yang terjadi terakhir kali, bukan?
It's okay. I should apologize too.
Tak apa-apa. Aku minta maaf juga. Aku menakutimu.
Did you have a bad dream or something?
Apa kau bermimpi buruk?
-Yes. -Is it related to your sleep disorder?
Ya.
As I've said before, you should try to think about something else.
Seperti yang kukatakan sebelumnya, kau harus memikirkan hal lain.
But I know it's not easy.
Aku tahu itu sulit.
You said you experienced something that reminded you of your past.
Katamu kau mengalami sesuatu yang mengingatkanmu akan masa lalumu.
Could you tell me about it?
Bisa kau ceritakan itu?
Will this be too hard as well?
Apa ini terlalu sulit?
I met people whose paths I never wanted to cross.
Aku bertemu orang yang tak ingin kutemui.
Who are they?
Siapa mereka?
They want to lock me up in my past.
Mereka mau mengurungku di masa lalu.
-Could you please elaborate? -They criticize me.
- Jelaskan. - Mereka mengkritikku.
They remind me of...
Mereka mengingatkanku pada...
my past.
masa laluku.
Your unhappy past... is not something to be criticized.
Masa lalumu yang tidak bahagia bukan hal yang harus dikritik.
No one can decide exactly how their life will unfold.
Tak ada yang bisa putuskan hidup mereka dengan pasti.
Is there something else?
Ada hal lain?
Do you not want to talk about it today?
Kau tak mau bicarakan hari ini?
Then there's nothing we can do today.
Maka tak ada yang bisa kita lakukan hari ini.
-I'm sorry. -It's okay.
- Maaf. - Tak apa-apa.
It looks like you need more time.
Kau butuh waktu.
But you know what?
Apa kau tahu?
You need to trust me more.
Kau harus lebih percaya padaku.
Let's have dinner together.
Ayo makan malam.
Sorry?
Maaf?
I don't spend time with my patients outside of the clinic--
Aku tak bertemu pasienku di luar klinik...
Don't read too much into it. Just have dinner with me.
Jangan terlalu dipikirkan. Ayo makan malam denganku.
Otherwise, we'll both have to eat alone.
Atau kita makan sendiri.
We never get hungry. Why do you want to eat at mealtimes like humans do?
Kita tak lapar. Kenapa kau mau makan di waktu makan manusia?
"Life itself is the proper binge,"
"Hidup adalah pesta yang tepat,"
said a human called Julia something.
kata manusia bernama Julia.
But we're not human.
Tapi kita bukan manusia.
You said you wanted to do all the lame things that humans do.
Katamu kau mau lakukan semua tindakan bodoh manusia.
I'm still angry. Do you know that?
Aku masih marah. Kau tahu?
-Sorry? -There are still hard feelings.
- Apa? - Masih ada kekesalan.
I just wanted to have dinner with you. Why did you push me away?
Aku hanya mau makan malam bersamamu. Kenapa menolak?
Well, I was just...
Aku hanya…
How do you form a friendship, Dr. Yun?
Bagaimana kau membuat persahabatan, Dokter Yun?
-Pardon? -You know what?
- Apa? - Apa kau tahu?
I know all about your financial situation,
Aku tahu situasi keuanganmu
and I also know how to push your buttons.
dan cara membuatmu marah.
I know how thoughtful you are,
Aku tahu kau bijak
and you're also very considerate, even though you act like you're not.
dan sangat perhatian meski sikapmu tak begitu.
You'd rather bear losses yourself.
Kau memilih menanggung rugi sendiri.
I know that enduring things is your hobby and specialty.
Menahan diri adalah hobi dan keahlianmu.
I also know who you like
Aku juga tahu siapa yang kau suka dan kenapa kau patah hati.
I learned about your childhood too.
Aku tahu masa kecilmu juga.
I know your address and resident registration number.
Bahkan alamat dan nomor KTP-mu.
Oh, sorry. I have a photographic memory.
Maaf. Aku punya ingatan fotografis.
It's not like I stalked you to obtain all this information.
Bukannya aku menguntitmu demi semua informasi ini.
You told me everything yourself.
Kau ceritakan sendiri semuanya.
You also know a lot about me.
Kau juga tahu banyak tentangku.
You've consoled and encouraged me.
Kau menghibur dan mendorongku.
Now, how can friendship grow from here?
Jadi, bagaimana bisa pertemanan tumbuh dari sini?
Are you saying we should become friends?
Kita harus berteman?
Don't you think we can be friends now?
Bisa kita berteman sekarang?
I'm rich. I also have a healthy mindset.
Aku kaya, pola pikirku sehat,
I'm commonsensical, polite, hardworking, and handsome.
logis, sopan, pekerja keras, tampan,
I even grow trees. I think I'm pretty awesome.
dan menanam pohon. Kurasa aku keren.
This is starting to hurt my pride.
Harga diriku mulai terluka.
It's not like I'm asking you to marry me. All I want is friendship.
Aku tak mengajakmu menikah.
Do I really have to list all of these things?
Apa aku harus membuat daftar semua itu?
Don't make a scene. Let's just leave.
Jangan buat gaduh. Kita pergi saja.
There's a restaurant I know. Let's go there.
Ada restoran yang kukenal. Ayo ke sana.
Jingeon, take her home.
Jingeon, antar dia pulang.
Do you really not know why he's being like that?
Kenapa dia begitu?
That can't be.
Tidak mungkin.
You know, don't you?
Kau tahu, 'kan?
Why is it that you never talk?
Kenapa kau tak pernah bicara?
Let's go. Come on.
Ayo pergi.
Do you know that I'm still a little mad at you?
Apa kau tahu aku masih agak marah padamu?
What?
Apa?
The hard feelings are still there.
Perasaan itu masih ada.
I'm quite picky too.
Aku juga pemilih.
It's not like I ask everyone to be my friend.
Aku tak meminta semua orang menjadi temanku.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
You really hold a grudge, don't you?
Kau sungguh memendam dendam, ya?
Then I have to say something too.
Aku mau katakan sesuatu.
You want us to be friends, yet you can't trust me.
Kau mau kita berteman, tapi tak percaya aku.
I'm your psychiatrist and friend, but your sessions are going nowhere.
Aku psikiater dan temanmu, tapi konsultasimu jalan di tempat.
How do you explain it?
Bisa jelaskan itu?
Is it because you can't trust me as a psychiatrist?
Kau tak percaya psikiatermu?
-No, that's not why. -Okay.
- Bukan itu. - Baiklah.
I can't force you to trust me. I'll make more effort instead.
Aku tak bisa memaksamu. Aku akan berusaha lebih keras.
And this plush toy is so cute.
Dan mainan ini sangat lucu.
I have to go.
Aku harus pergi.
Can I take that?
Boleh kuambil?
Isn't it cute? My friend and I designed it together.
Lucu, bukan? Temanku dan aku merancangnya.
It came with cups as a set, but all the cups have been sold.
Ada cangkirnya, tapi semua cangkirnya sudah terjual.
-How much-- -I'll pay.
- Berapa banyak... - Aku bayar.
What are you doing? I'm getting you a gift to celebrate our friendship.
Apa yang kau lakukan?
I'm too old to get a plush toy as a gift.
Aku terlalu tua untuk dapat hadiah boneka.
-How much is it? -It's 45,000 won.
- Berapa harganya? - Itu 15.000 won.
Hello?
Halo?
Okay. I'll leave right away.
Baik. Aku segera pergi.
It looks like I should get going. Something came up at the hotel.
Aku harus pergi. Ada suatu hal di hotel.
I had a great time today.
Aku senang hari ini.
I'm sorry I can't drive you home.
Maaf tak bisa mengantarmu.
Get home safely. I'll see you soon.
Hati-hati. Sampai jumpa.
HABAEK YUN SO-A
HABAEK, YUN SO-A
What is this place?
Tempat apa ini?
-Don't you remember? -Remember what?
- Kau tak ingat? - Ingat apa?
Why are you reading it silently? You're mean.
Kenapa baca diam-diam? Kau jahat.
You can't even read the first sentence aloud for me?
Kau tak bisa membaca kalimat pertama dengan lantang?
I'll tell you to stop reading if I don't like what I hear.
Akan kusuruh berhenti membaca jika aku tak suka.
I know it's embarrassing to read something out loud.
Membaca lantang memang menakutkan.
"How did we meet?
"Bagaimana kita bertemu?
One day, a butterfly flew like a petal
Suatu hari, seekor kupu-kupu terbang seperti kelopak bunga
and made a small flutter."
dan membuat kepakan kecil.
Once, I read the page of the book you used to read aloud to myself.
Aku pernah membaca halaman buku yang kau baca untuk diriku.
Once, I sat on the chair you used to sit on
Aku pernah duduk di kursi yang kau duduki
and closed my eyes
dan memejamkan mataku
in order to feel your warmth.
untuk merasakan kehangatanmu.
Once, I even caressed the rim of the cup you used to use
Aku bahkan pernah mengelus bibir cangkir yang biasa kau gunakan
with my fingertips.
dengan ujung jariku.
"How did we...
"Bagaimana kita bisa
manage to come this far together?
sampai sejauh ini bersama?
Were we able to reach love
Apa kita bisa meraih cinta
because we walked through such lovely moments together?
karena kita menjalani momen indah ini bersama?"
-An inevitable miracle." -"An inevitable miracle.
"Keajaiban yang tak terelakkan. "
I suppose I didn't want to think...
"Kurasa aku tak mau berpikir...
that we met by a mere coincidence.
kita bertemu karena kebetulan.
So,
Jadi...
the only thing I can do is do my best..."
hanya satu yang bisa kulakukan, yaitu berusaha sebaik mungkin..."
You can stop reading. Let's go eat now.
Kau bisa berhenti. Ayo makan.
I'll read the rest myself.
Akan kubaca sendiri sisanya.
"...to love you.
"...untuk mencintaimu.
At the moment,
Pada saat ini...
I am passing through your love."
aku sedang melewati cintamu. "
Why can't you do it for me?
Kenapa tak bisa melakukannya?
I want to keep coming here,
Aku ingin terus datang ke sini,
so you can just prepare the medication yourself.
jadi, kau bisa siapkan obatnya sendiri.
Why did he have to complain about such a thing?
Kenapa dia harus mengeluh soal itu?
Mr. Shin called earlier
Pak Shin menelepon tadi
and suggested sending the employees here directly from now on.
dan menyarankan mengirim karyawan kemari mulai sekarang.
-That would be nice. -See?
- Itu bagus. - Lihat?
He's the only one who understands you.
Hanya dia yang mengerti dirimu.
How does the afternoon look?
Bagaimana sore ini?
You have one appointment with Mr. Ma.
Kau ada janji dengan Pak Ma.
You said you were okay.
Kau bilang kau baik.
But you don't seem okay at all.
Kau tak tampak baik.
You kept talking about the winners, lessers, and losers.
Teruslah bicarakan pemenang, anak kecil, dan pecundang.
You kept bringing up that pretentious nonsense,
Kau terus mengungkit omong kosong. Lihat dirimu.
You seem as though you drank way more than you can handle.
Kau tampak mabuk melebihi kemampuanmu.
It looks like you're still struggling to sober up.
Masih berusaha untuk sadar.
That's obviously not the case
Jelas bukan karena itu...
-because I'm the one who dumped you. -You did.
- karena aku yang mencampakkanmu. - Benar.
But it doesn't feel like it, does it?
Rasanya tidak, bukan?
You're probably hating me for not being able to spot your lies.
Kau mungkin membenciku karena tak tahu kebohonganmu.
Do you realize it now?
Kini kau sadar itu?
It's impossible to not hurt anyone.
Mustahil tak menyakiti siapa pun.
Just like how the one who's loved by everyone is the worst person.
Seperti yang dicintai semua orang adalah orang terburuk.
I mean, think about that mysterious number you went on about.
Pikirkan soal angka misterius yang kau bicarakan.
live certain moments as if that day is going to be their last day.
seolah hari itu akan jadi hari terakhir mereka.
They instinctively know that they must live today in order to see tomorrow.
Secara naluriah mereka tahu mereka harus hidup hari ini untuk bertemu besok.
They don't live in fear that tomorrow may not be the same as today.
Mereka tak hidup dalam ketakutan besok mungkin berbeda dengan hari ini.
I'm talking about those who believe they can live
Mereka percaya mereka bisa hidup
the rest of their lives with the memories they've collected today.
hingga mati dengan kenangan yang mereka kumpulkan hari ini.
Isn't that much wiser than looking for an imaginary number
Bukankah itu lebih bijak daripada mencari nomor khayalan
to prevent everyone from getting hurt?
untuk mencegah semua orang terluka?
You said the square of an imaginary number ends up being less than zero.
Kau bilang kuadrat angka imajiner adalah kurang dari nol.
You're not even human.
Kau bahkan bukan manusia.
How come you never have an umbrella? You'll go bald.
Kenapa kau tak punya payung? Kau akan botak.
What?
Apa?
I guess she's still in love with that water demon.
Kurasa dia masih mencintai iblis air itu.
Goodness.
Astaga.
-What's up? -Come see me if you have some time.
- Apa kabar? - Temui aku jika kau punya waktu.
Yes.
Ya.
Habaek left.
Habaek pergi.
Did our servant tell you?
Apa pelayan kami memberitahu?
What a funny woman.
Wanita yang lucu.
What did she want in exchange?
Apa imbalannya?
Consolation? An alternative?
Penghiburan? Alternatif?
I wouldn't be asking you...
Aku tak bertanya jika aku tahu dari dari Nona Yun.
Fine. I came because I also have something to say.
Baik.
Please take care of her. No, actually...
Tolong jaga dia. Tidak, sebenarnya...
Yes.
Ya.
Just make her yours. You can have her.
Buat dia jadi milikmu. Kau bisa memilikinya.
A divine servant, my foot.
Pelayan dewa apanya.
We don't need her. We don't even care, but...
Kami tak butuh dia. Kami tak peduli, tapi…
This is just so annoying.
Ini menjengkelkan.
I'm not obsessed with being seen as the nice one.
Aku tak peduli pandangan orang.
-Are you trying to be responsible? -No, it's not that.
- Kau mencoba bertanggung jawab? - Tidak.
You may not believe me,
Kau mungkin tak percaya padaku,
but I don't think humans deserve to become miserable because of gods.
tapi aku tak berpikir manusia layak sengsara karena dewa.
-So-- -Then shouldn't you tell me...
- Jadi... - Seharusnya kau tak menyuruhku...
to make her happy...
membuatnya bahagia...
rather than tell me to just have her?
tapi memilikinya?
I don't care what you do. Just help her forget Habaek.
Aku tak peduli apa tindakanmu. Bantu dia melupakan Habaek.
That's not something I can easily do.
Itu tidak mudah.
Give it a try.
Cobalah.
You were planning on doing that anyway.
Kau berencana melakukannya.
And I want you to marry her. Stay by her side until the day she dies.
Dan nikahi dia.
Make sure no other man can even think about being with her.
Pastikan tak ada pria lain yang berpikir bisa bersamanya.
That's the only way we can completely cut off ties with her.
Hanya itu cara kita bisa memutuskan hubungan dengannya.
This must end for her own sake.
Ini harus berakhir demi dirinya sendiri.
I want you...
Aku ingin kau...
to help her.
membantunya.
What is it now?
Apa lagi sekarang?
You scared me. Why do you always show up so quietly...
Kau menakutiku.
and startle me?
dan mengejutkanku?
-Well, how much do you get paid monthly? -Why do you ask?
- Berapa kau dibayar bulanan? - Kenapa kau bertanya?
I'll pay you 1.5 times your wage to become my manager.
Kubayar 1,5 kali lipat jadi manajerku.
Really? I don't need that money.
Sungguh? Aku tak butuh uang.
I'll make it double.
Dua kali lipat.
All right, okay. Sit down.
Baiklah. Duduklah.
Then just keep being a good friend like you've always been.
Tetaplah menjadi teman baik seperti biasanya.
Do you really want counseling from me?
Kau mau konseling dariku?
Are you being serious?
Apa kau serius?
You said you'll do it if I pay you.
Katamu kau mau jika aku membayarmu.
If you're serious, there's something you need to do first.
Jika serius, ada yang harus kau lakukan dulu.
What's that?
Apa itu?
-Use honorifics when you call me. -What?
- Hormati aku. - Apa?
My gosh.
Astaga.
What kind of nonsense is that?
Omong kosong macam apa itu?
You don't want to do it?
Kau tak mau?
Forget it, then.
Lupakan saja.
Wait. Hey, how old are you?
Tunggu. Berapa usiamu?
From what I understand, we're the same age.
Setahuku usia kita sama.
Then I can't use honorifics. I was born in January.
Aku tak bisa pakai panggilan. Aku lahir bulan Januari.
I was born on January 1, at 12:01 a.m.
Aku lahir pada 1 Januari pukul 12.01.
-But why? -What do you mean?
- Kenapa? - Maksudmu?
You don't want counseling?
Kau tak mau konseling?
Forget it, then.
Lupakan saja.
Sir!
Pak!
Fine, I'll talk to you politely from now on.
Baik, aku sopan mulai sekarang.
Good. What is it that you want to talk to me about?
Bagus.
You didn't give me proper advice on what happened last time.
Kau tak memberiku nasihat yang tepat tentang apa yang terjadi terakhir kali.
Why do you think Mr. Shin hugged me from behind?
Kenapa Pak Shin memelukku dari belakang?
I wasn't mistaken.
Aku tidak salah.
He keeps acting like a bad guy.
Dia terus bersikap seperti penjahat.
Now that we've decided to do this properly,
Karena lakukan ini dengan benar,
I'll be responsible and give you proper advice.
akan kuberi saran yang tepat.
From what I understand, he's in love with your friend, Ms. Yun So-a.
Dari yang aku tahu, dia mencintai temanmu, Yun So-a.
So just drink some ice-cold water and come to your senses.
Jadi, minumlah air dingin dan sadarlah.
-What? -Now, it's crystal clear, right?
- Apa? - Itu jelas, bukan?
This is why all the girls at church always ask me for advice.
Ini sebab semua gadis di gereja minta nasihatku.
Grandpa, kick her out of your building. Kick her out right now!
Kakek, usir dia dari gedungmu. Usir dia sekarang!
You can't kick her out?
Tak bisa?
If you don't, I'll move back to the US. I'll go live with Mom!
Jika tidak, aku kembali ke AS.
I'm going to leave you!
Aku akan meninggalkanmu!
Why did you ask me to come by? I'm busy.
Kenapa memintaku datang? Aku sibuk.
Go back outside and come in again.
Keluar dan masuk lagi.
What?
Apa?
Why?
Kenapa?
My gosh, I don't even know. I should've just gone for it back then.
Astaga, entahlah. Seharusnya kuberi tahu dulu.
What are you saying? Why did you want to see me?
Apa? Kenapa mau menemuiku?
Have we done a birth chart reading?
Sudahkah aku meramalmu?
-Tell me your date and time of birth. -Gosh, don't bother.
- Katakan tanggal dan waktu lahirmu. - Tak perlu.
Just tell me. It's because you keep appearing in my dreams.
Katakan. Kau terus muncul di mimpiku.
I was born on-- Just a second.
Aku lahir...
Who's calling?
Siapa ini?
What's up? Is a patient waiting?
Apa? Apa pasien menunggu?
Dr. Yun!
Dr. Yun.
What? What's wrong?
Kenapa? Ada apa?
-Just take it out. -Please leave it there.
- Lepaskan saja. - Serahkan padaku.
-Just do as I say! -Gosh!
- Lakukan! - Astaga!
What is happening?
Apa yang terjadi?
"The contract ended a long time ago.
"Kontraknya sudah lama berakhir.
I can't let this go on. I won't put up with this anymore!"
Aku tak bisa biarkan ini. Aku tak tahan lagi! "
That's what the chairman said.
Itu yang dikatakan ketua.
"I'm an old man who lives off the rental income from this building.
"Aku orang tua yang hidup dari pendapatan sewa gedung ini.
My safety is being threatened because of that evil tenant."
Keamananku terancam karena penyewa jahat itu. "
Those were also his words.
Itu juga kata-katanya.
What are you talking about? I said I'll pay more deposit.
Apa maksudmu? Aku bilang aku akan bayar lebih banyak deposit.
Didn't you tell him?
Kau tak beri tahu dia?
I did, but he suddenly wants us out of here today no matter what.
Sudah, tapi dia tiba-tiba mau kita keluar hari ini.
Just leave it there!
Tinggalkan saja di sana!
What kind of nonsense is this?
Omong kosong macam apa ini?
Just leave that there, please!
Tolong tinggalkan di sana!
By the way, I heard that
Omong-omong, aku dengar
this was all decided by the chairman's beloved granddaughter,
semua ini diputuskan oleh cucu tercinta ketua,
Ms. Shin Ja-ya,
Nona Shin Ja-ya,
who is the real power behind the throne.
kekuatan sebenarnya di balik takhta.
Ms. Shin Ja-ya.
- Nona Shin Ja-ya. - Apa?
What did you say? Shin Ja-ya?
Apa katamu? Shin Ja-ya?
Take your filthy hands off everything.
Singkirkan tanganmu dari segalanya.
Mr. Ma.
Pak Ma.
Put everything back where it was. Don't move anything.
Kembalikan semuanya. Jangan pindahkan apa pun.
Hey, you! Put that down.
Hai, kau! Letakkan itu.
Mr. Ma, it's okay. It's nothing serious.
Pak Ma, tak apa-apa. Tak ada yang serius.
Don't get worked up. Just wait outside, please.
Jangan marah. Tolong tunggu di luar.
Don't touch anything.
Jangan sentuh apa pun.
Who says you can kick her out of this building?
Siapa bilang bisa mengusirnya?
I told you not to touch anything!
Kubilang jangan sentuh!
-What is your problem? -I told you not to touch anything!
- Apa masalahmu? - Kubilang jangan sentuh apa pun!
-Mr. Ma! -Don't touch anything!
- Pak Ma! - Jangan sentuh apa pun!
-Mr. Ma, stop! -Calm down!
- Pak Ma, hentikan! - Tenang!
-Mr. Ma! -You bastard!
- Pak Ma! - Bajingan!
Get out!
Keluar!
Be quiet!
Diam!
He's my patient.
Dia pasienku.
He has trouble controlling his emotions.
Dia kesulitan mengendalikan emosi.
I'm his psychiatrist. I'll take responsibility.
Aku dokternya. Aku tanggung.
Please let him go and--
Lepaskan dia dan...
We haven't been able to do anything because he's going bonkers.
Kami tak bisa berbuat apa-apa karena dia menggila.
How can we let him go?
Bagaimana melepaskannya?
Let's talk when his guardian gets here.
Mari bicara saat walinya datang.
Excuse me, Officer.
Permisi, Petugas.
I didn't even punch him once.
Aku bahkan tak memukulnya sekali pun.
That guy also participated in the assault,
Pria itu juga ikut menyerang, mereka berdua harus berdamai.
His guardian is out of the country at the moment.
Saat ini walinya sedang di luar negeri.
It'll take some time for someone else to come.
Butuh waktu untuk orang lain datang.
Don't shut down my psychiatrist's clinic! How could anyone with a heart do this?
Jangan tutup kliniknya!
You heartless bastard! You're--
Bajingan tak berperasaan! Kau...
Please be quiet!
Diam!
Ms. Yun.
Nona Yun.
Mr. Shin, I'm here!
Pak Shin, aku di sini!
-We're okay now. -Hello.
- Kita aman. - Halo.
Don't worry about these two. You should just...
Jangan cemaskan mereka.  Kau harus...
focus on dealing with the aftermath. Thank you.
fokus pada urusan setelahnya. Terima kasih.
I'll call you later.
Kutelepon nanti.
-May I hold your arm? -Pardon?
- Boleh kupegang tanganmu? - Apa?
You look like you're about to collapse.
Kau mau pingsan.
I'm all right.
Aku baik.
Why did Sang-yu do such a useless thing?
Kenapa Sang-yu lakukan hal sia-sia?
It's not useless. I'm so glad he did it.
Tak sia-sia. Aku senang dia melakukannya.
Give him a raise.
Naikkan gajinya.
I laughed a little after I got your call.
Aku tertawa setelah kau telepon.
I realized you probably don't have that many friends, just like me.
Aku sadar kau mungkin tak punya banyak teman, seperti aku.
Why did you have to be so difficult when I asked you to be my friend?
Kenapa kau sulit saat aku memintamu jadi temanku?
What do you say now? Isn't it nice to have a rich friend?
Kini bagaimana?
Do you want something to drink?
Kau mau minum?
-I just want to go home and rest. -All right, then.
- Aku ingin pulang dan beristirahat. - Baiklah.
Get in. I'll drive you home.
Akan kuantar.
It's not too far from here. I'll just walk.
Tak jauh. Aku jalan kaki saja.
The cool breeze will help me recollect myself.
Angin sejuk akan membantuku.
Okay.
Baiklah.
Then I'll call you later to make sure you got home safely.
Akan kutelepon nanti, memastikan kau selamat.
Thank you so much for today.
Terima kasih untuk hari ini.
Get home safely.
Hati-hati.
MR. SHIN HU-YE
PAK SHIN HU-YE
Hello?
Halo?
Are you home yet?
Kau sudah di rumah?
No, not yet.
Belum.
I knew it.
Sudah kuduga.
You said it's not far.
Katamu tak jauh.
I'm walking slowly.
Aku berjalan lambat.
Then I'll have to call you again to make sure you got home safely.
Nanti kutelepon lagi, memastikan kau sudah di rumah.
I recently found out that the granddaughter
Baru-baru ini aku tahu cucu pemilik gedung
of the building owner is a girl who hated me in school.
adalah gadis yang dulu membenciku di sekolah.
I don't even care to know what she's up to.
Aku bahkan tak peduli apa yang dia lakukan.
I wonder why she hates me so much.
Aku penasaran kenapa dia sangat membenciku.
We have a lot in common.
Kita punya banyak kesamaan.
Pardon?
Apa?
I'm also suffering because of those kinds of people.
Aku juga menderita karena orang macam itu.
What will you do about the clinic?
Bagaimana klinikmu?
I'll either have to meet the landlord and beg him to change his mind
Aku harus temui pemiliknya dan memohon agar berubah pikiran
or go see his granddaughter
atau temui cucunya
and beg her instead, I guess.
dan memohon padanya, mungkin.
Do you want me to go with you?
Mau aku temani?
I'm pretty good at threatening people.
Aku cukup ahli mengancam orang.
What?
Apa?
Or should I just buy that building?
Atau aku beli saja gedung itu?
I mean, I'm pretty rich myself.
Aku cukup kaya.
I'm being serious.
Aku serius.
I told you not to stay out late.
Kubilang jangan pulang larut.
You never listen to me, do you?
Kau tak pernah mendengarku.
Habaek is back.
Habaek kembali.
I came to say goodbye properly.
Aku mau pisah baik-baik.
I want to love you with no regrets.
Aku ingin tanpa penyesalan.
She is Habaek's woman. I was one step too late.
Dia wanita Habaek. Aku terlambat satu langkah.
The war begins now.
Perang dimulai sekarang.
If you can't win her heart,
Jika kau tak bisa memenangkan hatinya, ambil paksa.
Why do you keep acting like you don't know how I feel about you?
Kenapa kau seakan tak tahu perasaanku?
Is this real? Or am I dreaming?
Ini nyata? Aku bermimpi?
If this is a dream, I hope I never wake up.
Jika ini mimpi, aku tak mau bangun.
I'll wait. I'm good at waiting.
Akan kutunggu. Aku ahli menunggu.
Get away from him! I can't stand this.
Jauhi dia! Aku tak tahan lagi.
-Have you forgotten? -No way.
- Kau lupa? - Tak mungkin.
-I'm capable of... -I thought I was mistaken.
- Aku mampu... - Aku pikir aku salah.
...killing you guys.
...membunuh kalian.